# Vashistha Sharma (1) Featured

Pega CSSA Certified, Software developer in Pega 7.4, Pega PRPC, SOAP, SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript ,Bootstrap, WebServices, SQL-Server



Current Designation: Technical Lead Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 3 Months Current Company: Cognizant Technologies Solutions

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Pega, ms sql server, web services, css, bootstrap, html, pega, Pega PRPC, Pega Rules Process

Commander, SOAP

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 13-Jan-21 Last Modified: 8-Jan-21

### Summary

Software professional with 8 years of Overall experience in Pega and Microsoft Technologies.

Currently working in Cognizant Technologies Ltd as (Pega Developer) .

3.5 years of experience in developing applications using Pega Rules Process Commander.

Certified as PRPC System Architect in v7.4.

Understanding client requirements, mapping them to system requirements and incorporating changes in the project as required and having effective communication with clients.

Conversant with various aspects of application development like database design, and database optimization, design,

development, implementation, deployment, testing and support of application.

Understand Horizon Model and perform End to End process from Analysis to deployment and packaging

## Work Experience

Cognizant Technologies Solutions as Technical Lead

Apr 2019 to Till Date

Pega Development

Tech Mahindra as Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2014 to Apr 2019

Information gathering, Interaction with Client, development, Deployment, handling live bugs, Working on Agile model. Documented System Implementation Guide. Provide solutions to team.

WebDunia India Private Ltd. as Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2013 to Apr 2014

E2E process from analysis to deployment.

Infobeans India Private Ltd. as Software Engineer

Aug 2010 to Feb 2013

#### **Education**

UG: BCA (Computers) from Devi Ahilya Vishwa Vidhyalaya (DAVV), Indore in 2005

PG: MCA (Computers) from Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya (RGPV), Bhopal in 2008

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: CSSA: Pega Certified Senior System Archietect

CSA: Pega Certified System Architect

MCPD: Microsoft Certified Professional Developer MCTS: Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
Skill Name	Version	Last Oseu	Lxperience	
ASP NET	4.5	2015	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
MS SQL SERVER	2005,2008	2017	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
JavaScript, JQuery, XML, HTML, CSS		2017	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
OOPs/RDBMS		2016	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Windows XP, 2000 server				
Windows 7, Windows 2008R2	7,			
PEGA PRPC	7.2	2018	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Apache Tomcat		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
PostgreSQL		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
PEGA	7.4	2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			

#### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

#### **Work Authorization**

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa Countries: United Kingdom

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time